<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extra Fine Writer</title>
    <link>https://extrafinewriter.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Extra Fine Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 09:37:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://extrafinewriter.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://extrafinewriter.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 09:37:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://extrafinewriter.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am of the generation of people who can&amp;rsquo;t remember much about the old days when computers hasn&amp;rsquo;t become popular and word processing hasn&amp;rsquo;t become a thing. Back in the University, I wrote papers and my thesis with a computer word processor without using any pens, and it was as if the days of using any pens at all were numbered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was since I began to write &lt;a href=&#34;https://novelist.xyz/&#34;&gt;novels&lt;/a&gt; and, to a lesser extent, &lt;a href=&#34;https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/&#34;&gt;short stories&lt;/a&gt;, that I found myself turning back to pen and paper. Ballpoint pens, however, were inferior writing instruments, as they require users to press hard against the paper to write and create fatigue during long writing sessions, which are often necessary for writing lengthy prose work, such as a novel. A well-made fountain pens, however, can put ink on a piece of paper without any downward pressure, making long writing sessions possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There seems to be one more added benefit to using fountain pens: it allows user to get into the creative flow in a way not possible in a computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-extra-fine&#34;&gt;Why Extra Fine?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days of my conversion to fountain pens, I learned about fountain pens from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/sbrebrown&#34;&gt;S.B.R.E Brown&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/PenHabit&#34;&gt;Matt Armstrong&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s youtube videos.I soon noticed that they weren&amp;rsquo;t big fans of pens with fine or extra nibs. There are good reasons for preferring broader nibs, of course. For instance, broader nibs are bound to feel smoother. Consider Platinum #3776 Ultra Extra Fine nib: its tip is so sharp that writing with it is like digging into the paper, which creates the sensation of the nib&amp;rsquo;s not being smooth. Broader and flex nibs may also be fun to play with, if used with inks that have good shading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I use fountain pens to get things done: to write a lot of words on a notebook, sometimes in very small hand writing, especially when making changes and corrections between lines and at the margin. Having nice colours, good shading, or flexible nibs are kind of secondary to me. That means (Japanese) fine and extra fine nibs are the ideal nibs for my use case, though reviews of those kinds of pens seem lacking relative to broader nibs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is why I started this little website&amp;ndash;separate from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://novelist.xyz/&#34;&gt;main website&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;dedicated to fountain pens with fine and extra fine nibs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilot Custom Heritage 92 - Fine Nib</title>
      <link>https://extrafinewriter.com/pilot-custom-heritage-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 05:18:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://extrafinewriter.com/pilot-custom-heritage-92/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As much as I prefer Japanese fountain pens for their nibs with finer lines, there are a few compromises, one of which is the lack of &amp;ldquo;fancier&amp;rdquo; filling systems. Most Japanese fountain pens use proprietary cartridges or converters, even in some of the more expensive models. Pilot, to my knowledge, only has two models which don&amp;rsquo;t use cartridges/converters. One of them is Custom Heritage 823, which utilises a vacuum filling system. The other one, and the subject of this review, is Custom Heritage 92, which is a piston filler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japanese pens aren&amp;rsquo;t known for being adventurous in their designs, and most Japanese pens seem to fall into the &amp;ldquo;boring black pens&amp;rdquo; category, which I don&amp;rsquo;t mind a great deal, as what I care about most is how it writes. Though I do have a soft spot for clear demonstrator pens, and that makes Pilot Custom Heritage 92 an attractive pen for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://extrafinewriter.com/assets/img/pilot-custom-heritage-92-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pilot Custom Heritage 92&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Pilot Custom Heritage 92
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://extrafinewriter.com/assets/img/pilot-custom-heritage-92-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pilot Custom Heritage 92&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Pilot Custom Heritage 92
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;nib&#34;&gt;Nib&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pilot Custom Heritage 92 comes with only three nib options&amp;ndash;Fine, Medium, and Broad&amp;ndash;which are limited relative to some other Pilot pen models, such as Pilot Custom Heritage 91. That is a real shame that the two Pilot models which have the &amp;ldquo;fancier&amp;rdquo; filling systems&amp;ndash;Custom Heritage 92 and Custom Heritage 823&amp;ndash;have the least nib options available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://extrafinewriter.com/assets/img/pilot-custom-heritage-92-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pilot Custom Heritage 92 - F nib&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Pilot Custom Heritage 92 - F nib
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The one I have comes with a 14k Gold, rhodium plated Fine nib. Given that I tended to favour Japanese Extra Fine nib, I was worried that the Fine nib in this pen wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fine enough. To my surprise, however, this pen&amp;rsquo;s F nib gives a similar line width as Platinum #3776 EF nib.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nib is quite springy when compared with the EF nib on Platinum #3776, and it does give some line variations. I don&amp;rsquo;t think the EF nib on Platinum #3776 is scratchy, though the Pilot F nib is quite a bit smoother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing-sample&#34;&gt;Writing Sample&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Policy</title>
      <link>https://extrafinewriter.com/cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://extrafinewriter.com/cookie/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-cookies&#34;&gt;What Are Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is common practice with almost all professional websites, this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or &amp;lsquo;break&amp;rsquo; certain elements of the sites functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more general information on cookies see the Wikipedia article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie&#34;&gt;HTTP Cookies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-use-cookies&#34;&gt;How We Use Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use a cookie to remember whether or not you have agreed (or not) to our use of cookies on this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-party-cookies&#34;&gt;Third Party Cookies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use a certain third party cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case they are used to provide a service that you use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;cloudflare&#34;&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site uses Cloudflare to serve static resources and secure the site. As a part of Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s security feature, cookies are used for overriding a certain firewall settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on Cloudflare cookies, see the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170156-What-does-the-CloudFlare-cfduid-cookie-do-&#34;&gt;Cloudflare documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disabling-cookies&#34;&gt;Disabling Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of the this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-information&#34;&gt;More Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that has clarified things for you and as was previously mentioned if there is something that you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure whether you need or not it&amp;rsquo;s usually safer to leave cookies enabled in case it does interact with one of the features you use on our site. However if you are still looking for more information then you can contact us through one of our preferred contact methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:peter@novelist.xyz&#34;&gt;peter@novelist.xyz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>