<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on Extra Fine Writer</title>
    <link>https://extrafinewriter.com/tag/review/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on Extra Fine Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <atom:link href="https://extrafinewriter.com/tag/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilot Custom Heritage 92 - Fine Nib</title>
      <link>https://extrafinewriter.com/pilot-custom-heritage-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 05:18:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://extrafinewriter.com/pilot-custom-heritage-92/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As much as I prefer Japanese fountain pens for their nibs with finer lines, there are a few compromises, one of which is the lack of &amp;ldquo;fancier&amp;rdquo; filling systems. Most Japanese fountain pens use proprietary cartridges or converters, even in some of the more expensive models. Pilot, to my knowledge, only has two models which don&amp;rsquo;t use cartridges/converters. One of them is Custom Heritage 823, which utilises a vacuum filling system. The other one, and the subject of this review, is Custom Heritage 92, which is a piston filler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japanese pens aren&amp;rsquo;t known for being adventurous in their designs, and most Japanese pens seem to fall into the &amp;ldquo;boring black pens&amp;rdquo; category, which I don&amp;rsquo;t mind a great deal, as what I care about most is how it writes. Though I do have a soft spot for clear demonstrator pens, and that makes Pilot Custom Heritage 92 an attractive pen for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://extrafinewriter.com/assets/img/pilot-custom-heritage-92-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pilot Custom Heritage 92&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Pilot Custom Heritage 92
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://extrafinewriter.com/assets/img/pilot-custom-heritage-92-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pilot Custom Heritage 92&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Pilot Custom Heritage 92
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;nib&#34;&gt;Nib&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pilot Custom Heritage 92 comes with only three nib options&amp;ndash;Fine, Medium, and Broad&amp;ndash;which are limited relative to some other Pilot pen models, such as Pilot Custom Heritage 91. That is a real shame that the two Pilot models which have the &amp;ldquo;fancier&amp;rdquo; filling systems&amp;ndash;Custom Heritage 92 and Custom Heritage 823&amp;ndash;have the least nib options available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://extrafinewriter.com/assets/img/pilot-custom-heritage-92-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pilot Custom Heritage 92 - F nib&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
        Pilot Custom Heritage 92 - F nib
        
            
        
        &lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The one I have comes with a 14k Gold, rhodium plated Fine nib. Given that I tended to favour Japanese Extra Fine nib, I was worried that the Fine nib in this pen wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fine enough. To my surprise, however, this pen&amp;rsquo;s F nib gives a similar line width as Platinum #3776 EF nib.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nib is quite springy when compared with the EF nib on Platinum #3776, and it does give some line variations. I don&amp;rsquo;t think the EF nib on Platinum #3776 is scratchy, though the Pilot F nib is quite a bit smoother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing-sample&#34;&gt;Writing Sample&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>