<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extra Fine Writer</title>
    <link>https://extrafinewriter.com/tag/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Extra Fine Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <atom:link href="https://extrafinewriter.com/tag/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://extrafinewriter.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 09:37:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://extrafinewriter.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am of the generation of people who can&amp;rsquo;t remember much about the old days when computers hasn&amp;rsquo;t become popular and word processing hasn&amp;rsquo;t become a thing. Back in the University, I wrote papers and my thesis with a computer word processor without using any pens, and it was as if the days of using any pens at all were numbered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was since I began to write &lt;a href=&#34;https://novelist.xyz/&#34;&gt;novels&lt;/a&gt; and, to a lesser extent, &lt;a href=&#34;https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/&#34;&gt;short stories&lt;/a&gt;, that I found myself turning back to pen and paper. Ballpoint pens, however, were inferior writing instruments, as they require users to press hard against the paper to write and create fatigue during long writing sessions, which are often necessary for writing lengthy prose work, such as a novel. A well-made fountain pens, however, can put ink on a piece of paper without any downward pressure, making long writing sessions possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There seems to be one more added benefit to using fountain pens: it allows user to get into the creative flow in a way not possible in a computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-extra-fine&#34;&gt;Why Extra Fine?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early days of my conversion to fountain pens, I learned about fountain pens from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/sbrebrown&#34;&gt;S.B.R.E Brown&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/PenHabit&#34;&gt;Matt Armstrong&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s youtube videos.I soon noticed that they weren&amp;rsquo;t big fans of pens with fine or extra nibs. There are good reasons for preferring broader nibs, of course. For instance, broader nibs are bound to feel smoother. Consider Platinum #3776 Ultra Extra Fine nib: its tip is so sharp that writing with it is like digging into the paper, which creates the sensation of the nib&amp;rsquo;s not being smooth. Broader and flex nibs may also be fun to play with, if used with inks that have good shading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I use fountain pens to get things done: to write a lot of words on a notebook, sometimes in very small hand writing, especially when making changes and corrections between lines and at the margin. Having nice colours, good shading, or flexible nibs are kind of secondary to me. That means (Japanese) fine and extra fine nibs are the ideal nibs for my use case, though reviews of those kinds of pens seem lacking relative to broader nibs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is why I started this little website&amp;ndash;separate from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://novelist.xyz/&#34;&gt;main website&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;dedicated to fountain pens with fine and extra fine nibs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>